

Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Requirement Analysis, C++, Core Java, J2EE, Python, Servlets, JSP, HTML5, JavaScript, Angular 4, CSS3, JSON



Current Location: Nasik Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Mumbai, Pune Highest Degree: Master [Computer Science]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Requirement Analysis, C++, Core Java, J2EE, Python, Servlets, JSP, HTML5, JavaScript, Angular 4, CSS3, JSON

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Software Developer with around 5 years of JAVA/J2EE Enterprise Application Development experience in Client/Server and web based architecture systems.

Experienced in SDLC methodologies - Waterfall and Agile/Scrum methodology.

In-depth Knowledge of Core Java focusing on Concepts like Multithreading, Exception Handling, File handling, I/0, Generics, Data structures, Collections, Garbage Collection.

Experience in developing the Enterprise and Web applications using Java/J2EE technologies such as Servlets, JSP, HTML, Spring, Hibernate, Restful and SOAP Web services ,Jersey, XML,JSON,JDBC.

Developed User Interface using JSP, Servlet, JavaScript, Angular JS, CSS3 and HTML5.

Experience on front technology like JavaScript and Angular JS.

Experience with databases like MySQL, Oracle10g/11g/12g.

Good Expertise on Hadoop ecosystems (HDFS, Hive, Pig, Sqoop, MapReduce)

Work Experience

ConsultAdd Inc as Software Developer -JAVA/J2EE

Mar 2017 to Feb 2020

Responsibilities:

Involved in Requirements gathering, analysis, design, development, testing and Maintenance phases of Application. Involved in Daily Scrum (Agile) meetings, Sprint planning and estimation of the tasks for the user stories, participated in retrospective and presenting Demo at end of the sprint.

Developed endpoints using RESTful API and implemented logic to connect those endpoints then pull the real time data from various internal and external data sources and update the SQL database.

Developed the REST client to consume services.

Developed test framework for all micro services for Ingest API and validate the code and flow. Integrated the data with database.

Developed micro service architecture using Spring Boot and RESTful web services.

Developed Java API's using collections, Multithreading, Exception handling and Java I/O to fulfill the implantation of business logic.

Used Pentaho ETL tool for Extract, transform and load the external and internal data sources into SQL database.

Written SQL queries ad stored procedures to perform database operations.

Involved in Data/dimensional Modeling, Data Extraction/ Transformation/ Loading (ETL) and Data mapping Using Pentaho ETL tool

Used Python and Java to automate the entire ETL job process.

Used python and java for JSON processing, data exchange and business logic implementations.

Posted ETL job results on Elasticsearch.

Created dashboard to visualize and monitored data in Kibana.

Involved in creating Hive Tables, writing Hive queries and load the data into MELD - Massive Event level data (Comcast Big Data Platform)

Developed and executed shell scripts to pull data from multiple sources and ingest data to MELD.

Written Hive queries for data analysis and perform various data operations to meet the Business requirements.

Developed sgoop scripts to transfer the data from Oracle database to Hadoop (MELD - Big data platform).

Used DIFA tool to create workflow process and use UC4 tool to automate and run those workflows to migrate the data from traditional databases to non-relational databases.

Configured Presto tool so business user can view the source data.

JIRA used for project tracking and bug fixing.

Involved in building the code using Maven & deployed it on server.

Involved in JUNIT testing using Mockito.

Used GIT for source code version controlling.

Environment: Agile/Scrum, Java 1.7/1.8, Oracle 12c, Python2/3, GitHub, Shell, Spring framework 4.3, Pentaho (ETL tool), Hadoop, Hive, Sqoop/DIFA, , JUnit 4/5, Mockito, Postman, RESTFul Web services, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, WinScp, Putty Client, UC4 automation tool

Employer: ConsultAdd Inc

Client: Verizon Wireless, USA (March 2017 - Dec 2017)

Role: Java Web Developer Project: E-Credit Modernization

Responsibilities

Developed all the UI pages using Angular 2/4, Node JS, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, JavaScript, Ajax.

Developed dynamic responsive Web Application by integrating Angular with Bootstrap which is further integrated with

REST Web Services

Developed Angular2, Angular4 components in TypeScript for web-based application.

Created Angular2 & Angular4 Components, Pipes, Injectables across the whole system, such as build custom filter and the main assortment dashboard.

Created Typescript reusable components and services to consume REST API's using component based architecture provided by Angular2

Used Node Js as proxy to interact with Rest services and with Database, building real-time Web API's

Implemented Angular 2 CSRF, XSS strategy to protect an application.

Handled all aspects of the web application including maintaining, testing, debugging and deploying. Highly used Angular2,

Angular 4 Router to build single page applications for navigation through the different status and multiple modals.

Debug the issue in firebug for Firefox, web developer tools in Chrome, Safari and IE 8,9,10 browsers.

Used Spring annotations to simplify the business logic for creating Spring MVCRestful web services.

ZionTech Solution Inc as Software Developer

Jul 2016 to Feb 2017

Responsibilities:

Involved in the Analysis, Design and implementation using AGILE methodology for iterative development of the application. Participated in Scrum Meetings.

Used Spring MVC Framework for integrating various Java Components

Developed application using Spring, Hibernate, Web Services (RESTFUL)

Developed and Consumes Restful web services and tested using SOAP UI

Used Spring ORM module to integrate with Hibernate.

Wrote front end with HTML, JSP and CSS and Developed client side validations using JavaScript.

Used Angular JS for login and developed controller for registration

Developed the DAO layer using the Hibernate annotations and configuration files

Worked on MySQL as the backend database.

Involved in writing SQL queries and Stored Procedures of tables from MySQL.

Used Maven as Build and Configuration Tool.

Used Jenkins as continuous integration tool

Deploy the application on WebLogic Application Server.

Used Log4J to capture the logging information and JUnit to test the application classes.

Used GIT Repository for Source Code maintenance

Environment: Java/J2EE, HTML/XML, CSS, Angular JS, JavaScript, JSP, Spring, Hibernate, Rest Web Services, SOAP UI, Junit, MySQL, Maven, Jenkins, Apache Tomcat, Web Logic

APSC InfoTech & Software Solution Pvt. Ltd. as Java Developer

Aug 2012 to Mar 2014

Title: ERP Management System for Manufacturing

Description: APSC InfoTech provides a comprehensive enterprise resource Planning system that offers best-practice support for multi-mode manufacturers in a broad range of Industries. Manufacturing ERP is designed for manufacturing excellence with visibility throughout the operation and embedded support for a wide variety of manufacturing processes.

Responsibility:

Developed application using AGILE methodology for iterative development of the application.

Involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) of the application like Requirement gathering,

Design, Analysis and Code development.

Developed and design UI with JSP, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS and validated with JavaScript.

Developed Web-module using Spring MVC Framework.

Integrated Spring framework with Hibernate ORM tool to access the MySQL database.

Developed and consumed Restful web services using Jersey framework and tested using SOAP UI.

Developed & Execute Unit test plans using JUnit & Documented Test Plan & Test Case.

Used Tomcat Web Server to deploy the application & Used Maven as Build Tool.

Environment: JSP, Servlet, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Hibernate, Spring MVC Framework, MySQL, Maven, Apache Tomcat Server, Eclipse, WebLogic Application Server, RESTfull Web Service, SOAP UI, GIT.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from University Of Pune in 2012

PG: Master (Computer Science) from Northwestern Polytechnic University USA in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C++, Core Java, J2EE, Python			
Servlets, JSP, HTML5, JavaScript			
Angular 4, CSS3, JSON, XML, XSLT			
JDBC, MySQL, Oracle-10g/11g			
HDFS, Hive, Sqoop, Map Reduce			
RESTFULL, SOAP			
Hibernate, Spring4/3			
Jersey, AXIS, JAXB, JAX-RS , JAX-WS			
Apache Tomcat, Oracle Web Logic			
Eclipse, NetBeans			
MS Visual Studio 2010, Intellij			
Windows, Unix, Linux			
Maven, Jenkins, Microstrategy			
Git Hub			
TCP/IP, ISO & OSI Model			
Windows XP/7/8 ,Unix ,Linux			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=eda4aae29419450a5c5e06db93b179fc515c09021b100b420743425d5...

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time